Aayam K. Shrestha

Linkedin.com/in/aayamshrestha

Email: shrestaa@oregonstate.edu Github.com/idigitopia | (+1) 541-368-8894

STATEMENT

Hoping to play my part on not just solving intelligence, but more importantly ensuring that its intent aligns with ours. Believer of a digitopia and a spiritual seeker. Current Research: Deep Grounding of AI planners, Bridging the gap between symbolic planners and data-driven learners.

Research Interests: Deep Reinforcement Learning, Explainable AI, Knowledge Graphs.

EDUCATION

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR

PhD. in Computer Science; GPA: 3.85/4.0

Sept. 2018 - Sept 2023 [Expected]

Kathmandu Engineering College, Tribhuvan University

Kathmandu, Nepal Aug. 2012 - Apr. 2016

Bachelors in Computer Engineering; GPA: 4.0/4.0 (Valedictorian)

EXPERIENCE

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR

Graduate Research Assistant — Advisor : Prof. Alan Fern

Sept. 2018 - Present

• Research: Deep Reinforcement Learning and Symbolic Reasoning/Planning. • Project: Part of the OSUs team for DARPA Machine Common Sense Project .

IDEA Lab - Team member — Advisor : Prof. Arash Termehchy

June 2018 - Feb. 2019

• Research: Working in the intersection of knowledge graphs and Machine Learning.

Logic Information Systems.

Blommington, MN May 2016 - Aug. 2018

Business Intelligence Engineer

- o Project: Develop and maintain large-scale enterprise Data Warehousing and Business Intelligence solutions
- o BI Consulting: Off-shore consulting for clients Alex & Ani, Holland and Barett, Gander Mountain, and Makro.
- Research: Customer Experience Analytics over in-house data lake. Data Sources: customer call audio, text reviews and curated twitter feeds.

Skills and Tools

- Languages: Python, C#, R.
- Frameworks and Libraries: Pytorch, Tensorflow, Pandas, Wandb, SKlearn, Hadoop, Spark, ASP.NET, GraphQL
- Databases: MySQL, MsSQL, OraclePL/SQL, Netezza, Teradata, Cypher-Neo4J
- Default Stack: Numpy, Pytorch, SKlearn, Pandas, Wandb

Publications

- 1. Aayam Shrestha, Stefan Lee, Prasad Tadepalli and Alan Fern. "DeepAveragers: Offline Reinforcement Learning by Solving Derived Non-Parametric MDPs". Under Review, ICLR 2021. (pdf)
- 2. Aayam Shrestha, Stefan Lee, Prasad Tadepalli and Alan Fern. "DeepAveragers: Offline Reinforcement Learning by Solving Derived Non-Parametric MDPs". Offline Reinforcement Learning Workshop, NeurIPS 2020 (Oral). (pdf)
- 3. Yodsawalai Chodpathumwan, Aayam Shrestha, Stephen Ramsey, Arash Termehchy. "Structurally Robust Similarity Search". Under Review, SIGMOD 2021. (pdf)

Projects

- DAC-MDPs: Deriving non parametric MDPs for Offline Reinforcement learning and zero-shot transfer learning. (2020)
- BigMDP: Library for creating and solving large MDPs with million of states. GPU optimized VI solver. (2019)
- Semi Supervised Mars Imageset Classification: Using k-means clustering over discrete learned features. (2019)
- Obj2Obj GAN: Masked Image to Image translation using GANs for object inpainting. (2018)
- Bias in Knowledge Graphs: Identifying bias of ML algorithms for different information preserving variations (2018)
- Vehicle Traffic Prediction: For optimizing traffic flow using RNNs on real world dataset. (2017)
- Gurukul: Integrating analytics and data-driven recommendations for College ERP (2015)